# **HARITHA RAGHU**

WEB DEVELOPER

+91 6282059552

https://haritharaghu.netlify.app

https://github.com/HarithaRaghu https://www.linkedin.com/in/harith <u>a-raghu-b03b60146</u>

#### **ABOUT ME**

Innovative, solution-focused Web developer with 2+ years of experience in IT industry. Committed to writing clean, efficient and maintainable code. Clear understanding of modern technologies and best design practices. Strong technical, analytical and interpersonal skills. Highly responsible and adaptable.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

(03/2021 - Present) PROJECT ENGINEER, WIPRO TECHNOLOGIES

Software Engineer L2, React JS Developer (04/2022-Present)

- Technology Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Bootstrap, GIT, Sass, MongoDB, TypeScript
- Involved in designing webpages using React JS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, TypeScript, MongoDB
- Used React-Router to turn the application into Single Page Application.
- Worked on using React components, Forms, Events and Router
- Designed reusable components and major pages with navigation bars using React JS
- Experience with Front-end development with back-end system integration
- Experience in Restful API and web services to integrate between server side and client side code
- Used Git for version controlling and regularly pushed code to GitHub
- Worked on web Accessibility which helps to boost the usability of the site for all users.
- Worked on Agile(scrum) development team to deliver regular updates to business team and project managers

## Software Engineer, Junior Front End Developer (03/2021-04/2022)

- Design, develop and test HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript that meets accessibility and web browser standards for website
- Performing bug fixes and code reviews
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure consistency in UI design and functionality

## **PROJECTS**

#### Portfolio Website Using React JS

- Responsive Portfolio Website with contact form submission and has Google Tag Manager integrated into the website for tracking page views and events.
- Link: https://haritharaghu.netlify.app
- Technology Stack: React JS, Sass, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GIT

### **Responsive Ecommerce Website**

 Created Ecommerce websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript Link: <a href="https://spurshop.netlify.app/">https://spurshop.netlify.app/</a>

## Blockchain-Based Government Project Fund Tracking and Management System.

- Adding permissioned support of hyperledger fabric to government fund distribution system.
- Tools & Technology Stack: Hyperledger fabric, Visual Studio Code, Docker, MongoDB, Node JS, cURL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

## **SKILLS**

## Programming Languages

- Java JavaScript
- SQL(MySQL)
- Python

## Web Technology

- HTML
- CSS React
- Bootstrap
- MERN Stack

## Tools and Technologies

- Version control(GIT)
- VS code
- Eclipse
- IBM App Connect Enterprise
- Web Services(RESTful)

## **TRAININGS UNDERGONE**

- JAVA J2EE
- IBM API Connect
- Python Scripting
- IBM API Connect
- Internship ICT ACADEMY (10/7/17 - 14/7/17), Cyberpark Calicut Microsoft Office, C Programming

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- AZ-900:Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Microsoft | (12/2022)
- IBM Certified Solution Implementer API Connect v10.0.3-IBM | (11/2022)
- Java J2EE Wipro Technologies
- Learn Complete Front End Web Development with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 5, JavaScript, ECMAScript 6, Angular & React JS- WIPRO Limited |Udemy | (07/2022)
- Database Programming with PL/SQL ORACLE Academy | (10/2018)

## **EDUCATION**

**BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY** (2016-2020)

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University

**CGPA-7.85**